GRANT CAWLEY

Charlotte, NC 28206

Phone: (636) 368-7221 • Email: grantlcawley@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/grant-l-cawley/

GitHub: https://github.com/cawleygl • Portfolio: https://cawley-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer utilizing background in psychology to create dynamic new experiences and continue pursuit of learning. Prioritizes thinking from the perspective of the user to create new user functionality in online spaces. Dedicated problem-solver known for being a team player.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools and Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Github, jQuery, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bootstrap, Heroku, REST APIs, MERN, Handlebars.js, Responsive Design, Progressive Web Applications (PWAs), Local Storage, Visual Studio Code, Chrome DevTools **Languages:** English, Conversational Spanish

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2022 – Present

Capgemini - Charlotte, NC

Continued learning and applying new technologies and software development fundamentals as a part of Capgemini's Next Generation Talent program.

Junior Frontend Developer

2021 - 2022

HopDrive - Richmond, VA

Used problem-solving, teamwork, and web development skills to improve applications that aided in moving professional vehicles for other businesses and organizations. *Key Accomplishments:*

Delivered new tools that integrated functionality using API's from outside organizations.

PROJECTS

Blackjack Casino & Multiplayer Blackjack Casino • https://github.com/EgiVilza/Casino Multiplayer • https://github.com/EgiVilza/Project2 • https://frozen-wildwood-18963.herokuapp.com

- Summary: A web application that allows the user to play Blackjack and save their score to a
 database. The updated multiplayer version allows users to sign up and play with others online
 using WebSockets.
- Role: Front-End and Back-End Developer
- Tools: React, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express, Socket.io, MongoDB, Mongoose

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

2020 - 2021

Washington University - St. Louis, MO

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, & React.

Bachelor of Science in Psychology Bachelor of Science in Spanish

2014 - 2018

Saint Louis University - St. Louis, MO

LEADERSHIP

President: League of Laughter Improv Comedy Club

2016 - 2018

Saint Louis University - St. Louis, MO

Facilitated official club activities, planned and coordinated shows and other events, and ran club meetings in their entirety.